

KELLY MARIA HILL

420 W. Slaughter Lane, Apt. #417 • Austin, TX 78748 • (504) 432-8327 • <u>Kelly.m.hill2115@gmail.com</u> https://codefitness21.github.io/Portfolio/ • https://github.com/Codefitness21?tab=repositories

SUMMARY

Junior front end developer, with project experience across front end web development. Key strengths include consulting with clients to develop personalized health solutions, creating and delivering educational presentations, and applying technology to real-world challenges. Analytical thinker and creative problem solver, able to quickly learn, apply, and troubleshoot new technologies in fast-paced environments.

SKILLS PROFILE

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, some JavaScript, learning Vue.js

Platforms/Design Tools: GitHub, Visual Studio Code / Adobe XD, Figma, Photoshop, Procreate

Workshops/ Classes: Austin Coding Academy – Learn to Code

Girls in Tech Coding Bootcamp: Intro to JS Developer Week Hackathon Conference Black Women Talk Tech – Austin Chapter Women Who Code: Hacking Hangout Codecademy – Web Development Khan Academy – HTML, CSS, JS

Udemy – Current: The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp, API and Web Service Introduction, Modern JavaScript from the beginning 2.0 - 2023 Revamp

EXPERIENCE

2021 – Present Digital Seat Media Austin, TX-(Remote)

Junior Front End Developer

- Responsible for gathering assets as it relates to rosters, school logo, colors, and schedule logos and assembling collegiate and professional sports apps in a JSON editor using the assets and approved application modules assigned through JIRA tickets.
- Wireframing and prototyping low and high fidelity mock-ups using Adobe XD and Figma for company and personal apps and websites.
- Team skill building lessons surrounding JavaScript as well as Photoshop to transform images and implement them into company and personal apps and websites.

Certified Personal Trainer/Nutritionist/Metabolic Technician

- Assess the nutritional and physical health of clients and collaborate to implement holistic fitness
 programs addressing specific health needs, in addition to providing tools to support continual
 advancement in both the fitness center and at home.
- Utilize a range of technological tools, application software, and technical solutions to assess caloric intake, resting metabolic rate, and active metabolic rate to develop customized plans and monitor progress.
- Collaborate with the metabolic specialist and tech team to share knowledge, analytical data, and technical solutions to promote sustainable client progress and success.

2016 – 2017 24 Hour Fitness Austin, TX

Certified Personal Trainer

- Designed individualized exercise programs tailored to the goals and needs of clients.
- Advised clients on proper nutritional planning and demonstrated use of fitness apps to help track progress.

2012 – 2015 Texas State University San Marcos, TX

Dietetic Intern 2014 – 2015

- Led nutrition groups and conducted screenings and assessments for patients.
- Created and delivered presentations on recommendations and education to patients, athletes, and fellow students.

Graduate Assistant 2012 – 2013

 Instructed a Nutrition Food Systems laboratory, and assisted the professor with research and grant writing, in addition to grading exams and research papers.

PROJECTS

Medical App Present

 Currently building this app using vue.js to help anesthesiologists better assist their patients as it relates to preoperative care.

Portfolio 2022

Created a portfolio from scratch using HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, and hand drawn art to store
projects. Procreate and Photoshop were also used to facilitate creating the art work displayed
throughout the project.

Sports Betting App 2022

 Created an app demonstrating the ease of navigation among several sports, teams, and games with the option of placing several bets.

Digital Seat Website 2022

 A re-designed web page project, utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that displays the cutting edge technology of the company as well as information pertaining to fan engagement.

Let's Get Motivated 2019

 Utilized JavaScript to create an application generating random motivational quotes to support fitness aspirations.

EDUCATION

Texas State University

San Marcos, TX

Master of Science, Human Nutrition (2015)

University of New Orleans

New Orleans, LA

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology (2004)